Guide to the Meyer Chessin Papers 1930-1992
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Meyer Chesin Papers
1930-1992
University of Montana--Missoula Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana--Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 630
Chessin, Meyer
21.8 linear feet
This collection contains papers, which represent Meyer Chessin’s education at the University of California and career as a Plant Physiologist at The University of Montana; these paper include correspondence, publications, research materials, teaching papers, service papers, and some audio-visual materials.
Biography of Meyer Chessin
Meyer “Mike” Chessin was born on February 2, 1921 in New York City. He moved to California at age 16. After high school, he attended UCLA and received an A.A. degree in Plant studies in 1939. Chessin then attended UC-Berkeley where he received a B.S. degree in Plant Pathology in 1941. He enlisted in the military in 1943. While serving in the military, Chessin attended three semesters of communication engineering courses at Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio. While in Columbus he met his wife, Florence. In 1945, Chessin served abroad in Kwajalein Island, Marshall Islands and Berlin, Germany.
Chessin left the military in 1946 and attended UC-Berkley, earning his Ph.D. in Plant Physiology in 1950. Chessin moved to Missoula and began work as a professor at The University of Montana, Department of Botany in 1949. He worked at the University until his retirement in 1990, when he received professor emeriti status.
Chessin’s scholarly research interests included plant physiology, pathology, photobiology and virology. He was an active researcher and collaborated in domestic and foreign research. He completed fellowships in plant pathology at Harpenden, England and in physical chemistry at the University of Minnesota. He attended institutes on both desert and tropical biology in Arizona and Costa Rica respectively. He directed research for the Bi-national Agricultural Research and Development (BARD) program based in Israel from 1975-1981. He served as a Fulbright lecturer traveling to Romania in 1971 and 1975 and to Bulgaria in 1980. He served as a consulting editor for Environment magazine.
Chessin was also interested in broader environmental and civic issues including herbicides and pesticides, solid waste management, the effects of nuclear weapons and radiation and disarmament. Chessin advised state and local Weed Management committees on herbicides and biological control issues. He was instrumental in establishing the Western Montana Scientists Committee for Public Information, which conducted public Solid Waste Workshops throughout Montana and Idaho. Chessin has been a peace activist since 1946. In a 2003 interview for the Veterans History Project, Chessin credits his military experience with sparking his interest in the peace movement and disarmament.
This collection contains papers which represent Meyer Chessin’s education and career; these include correspondence, publications, research materials, teaching papers, service papers, and some audio-visual materials.
Series I, Correspondence, predominately contains professional correspondence and a small amount of personal correspondence. Correspondents include colleagues, publishers, politicians, government officials, scholarly organizations and businesses. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent and chronologically by date.
Series II, Writings and Publications, contains scholarly research, civic and environmental publications. Over fifty publications were described at the item-level; the remaining publications and writings are unorganized. The organized publications in this series are arranged alphabetically.
Series III, Teaching Papers, contains papers from both undergraduate and graduate courses Chessin taught. These include lecture notes, exams, quizzes, reading materials, lab manuals, experiments, and correspondence regarding seminar speakers. There is one linear foot of papers, reports and assignments students prepared for Chessin’s courses.
Series IV, University and Academic Service Papers, contains papers from Chessin’s academic and University service. It is divided into two subseries: Subseries 1, General Service Papers and Subseries 2, Restricted Service Papers.
Subseries 1, General Service Papers, contains correspondence, reports, newsletters and meeting minutes. Chessin’s academic service materials include papers from scholarly organizations focused on plant pathology and photobiology. There are also materials from national and international conferences and symposiums. University service papers include: Faculty Senate and committee meeting minutes and correspondence; University and Botany department correspondence, memos and curriculum reviews; Chessin’s service record; formal requests for sabbatical leave; and University news releases noting Chessin’s achievements. The faculty committees represented in the subseries are the Budget and Policy Committee, the Executive Committee, the Faculty Benefits Committee, the Faculty Research Advisory Committee and the Hazards Radiation Committee. One folder contains correspondence and records of Joseph Kramer, an early Botany faculty member and dates from 1930-1977. This subseries is organized alphabetically.
Subseries 2, Restricted Service papers, contains restricted papers from the Faculty Appeals Committee, student advisees, faculty searches and an age discrimination complaint. This series is restricted.
Series V, Research Papers, contains articles, correspondence, notes, research data, grant and fellowship applications and research proposals and reports. Chessin’s research subjects included cactus viruses and hosts, photobiology, photo reactivation, selenium, spiderwort and radiation. His records regarding foreign travel and foreign research collaboration are included in this collection. This series also contains research Chessin completed for his doctorial dissertation. This series is arranged alphabetically.
Series VI, Civic and Environmental Service Papers, contains articles, clippings, correspondence, reports, newsletters, meeting minutes, and reports about social and environmental topics. These topics include: militarism, nuclear weapons, radiation, disarmament, hazardous waste, herbicides and pesticides, solid waste management and recycling. Records of the Western Montana Scientists Committee for Public Information (WMSCPI) and the solid waste workshops it sponsored are included in this series. This series contains correspondence with politicians and government officials regarding military and environmental topics. This collection also contains Chessin’s preparatory notes and articles for his testimony about 2,4,5-T before the EPA, Office of Hazardous Materials Control. This series is arranged alphabetically.
Series VII, College Papers, contains papers from Chessin’s time as a student at UCLA and UC-Berkeley. These include class notes, papers, drawings, research notes. This series is organized alphabetically.
Series VIII, Miscellaneous Papers, contains unidentified handwritten notes, clippings, a map, a calendar, and supplier information. This series is organized alphabetically.
Series IX, Photographs and Slides, contains photographs, negatives, photographic slides and specimen slides. Subjects include Cactus Virus, BARD, King Cole’s Hole, herbicide’s effects on animals and plant species at an unidentified botanical garden. There are audio cassettes that accompany the King Cole’s Hole slides and herbicide’s effects on animals negatives.
The collection is divided into nine series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1.0 linear feet, circa 1950s-1986
Series II: Writings and Publications, 1.0 linear feet, 1950-1992
Series III: Teaching Papers, 3.0 linear feet, circa 1949-1980s
Series IV: University and Academic Service Papers, 5.4 linear feet, 1930-1980
Subseries 1: General Service Papers, 3.0 linear feet, 1930-1980 and undated
Subseries 2: Restricted Service Papers, 2.4 linear feet, 1969-1990
Series V: Research Papers, 4.6 linear feet, [circa 1947-1990]
Series VI: Civic and Environmental Service Papers, 4.4 linear feet, 1959-1982
Series VII: College Papers, 1.0 linear feet, 1940-1948
Series VIII: Miscellaneous Papers, 0.4 linear feet, 1974
Series IX: Photographs and Slides, 1.0 linear feet, 1971-1975
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana--Missoula. Materials in Series IV, Subseries 2 are restricted.
Papers were held by Meyer Chessin until he donated them to the Archives.
This collection was a donated by Meyer Chessin in three parts in 1992, 1994 and 1995.
During processing, a number of published materials were removed. Floor plans for the proposed Stella Duncan Research Institute and proposed Health Sciences Building were removed from the collection due to severe water damage and mold.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
University of Montana-Missoula--Faculty; University of Montana (Missoula, Mont.). Dept. of Botany; Western Montana Scientists' Committee for Public Information
Cactus--Diseases and pests; Disarmament; Hazardous wastes; Herbicides; Militarism; Nuclear weapons; Peace movements--United States; Pesticides; Photobiology--Study and teaching--Montana--Missoula; Plant diseases--Study and teaching--Montana--Missoula; Radiation; Recycling (Waste, etc.); Refuse and refuse disposal; Selenium; Tradescantia
Photographs
Colleges and Universities; Environmental Conditions; Montana; Science
College teachers--Montana--Missoula; Environmentalists--Montana--Missoula
- Correspondence, circa 1950s-1986; Series I; 1.0 linear foot
  - Champion International, 1986 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Baucus, Max, 1977 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Benson, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - General B. Gurwitz, undated (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Louis Hayes, 1980 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - P. E. Libby, 1980 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Michael Mawby, undated (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Lloyd Meyer, undated (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Puskar G. Rawal, undated (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Correspondence, foreign travel, undated (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Correspondence, plant importation, undated (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Correspondence, Troy, Montana, undated (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Correspondence, prior to 1960 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box-folder 1/16)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box-folder 1/17)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Correspondence, 1965 and undated (Box-folder 1/20)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 1/21)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 1/22)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1979 (Box-folder 1/23)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box-folder 1/24)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box-folder 1/25)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box-folder 1/26)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 1/27)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box-folder 1/28)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 1/29)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 1/30)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box-folder 1/31-38)
- Writings and Publications, 1950-1992; Series II; 1.0 linear foot
  - "Abolition of Glandular Secretion by Ultraviolet Light", 1962 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - "Cacti, Too, Have Viruses", 1963 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - "Cactus Virus in the United States", 1961 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - "Calcium Deficiency and Infection of Nicotiana glutinosa by Tobacco Mosaic virus," by Chessin and H. A. Scott, 1955 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - "Civil Defense Hazards Associated with Intercontinental Ballistic Missile Installations in Central Montana," notes and correspondence, 1963-1981 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - "Chloroplast ‘Disappearance’ as a Tool for Studying Some Effects of Ultraviolet Light on Plants," by M. Chessin and G. H. Quinn Jr., 1961 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - "Disappearance of Guard Cell Chloroplast in Ultraviolet-Irradiated Leaves," by L.M. Blakely and M. Chessin, 1959 (Box-folder 2/7)
  - "Differential Sensitivity of Tobacco Mosaic Virus and Its Infection Nucleic Acid to Fast Electrons," by M. Chessin, R. A. Solberg and M. Jackson, 1964 (Box-folder 2/8)
  - "A Distinctive Strain of Ribgrass Mosaic Virus from Montana, USA", 1980 (Box-folder 2/9)
  - "Distribution of Cactus Viruses in Wild Plants," by M. Chessin and D. Lesemann, 1972 (Box-folder 2/10)
  - "Dormancy in Some Western Montana Shrubs", 1955 (Box-folder 2/11)
  - "Effects of Auxins on Virus-Induced Leaf Abscission," by Joan Gwyneth Byson and M. Chessin, 1961 (Box-folder 2/12)
  - "The Effect of Nitrogen Deficiency on the Properties of Tobacco-Mosaic Virus", 1951 (Box-folder 2/13)
  - "Effects of Radiation on viruses," manuscript, undated (Box-folder 2/14)
  - "Effects of Tobacco mosaic Virus on Early Leaf Development in Tobacco," by Sanford S. Tepfer and M. Chessin, 1959 (Box-folder 2/15)
  - "An Electron Microscope Study on the Size of Sammons’ Opuntia Virus", 1965 (Box-folder 2/16)
  - "External Symptoms and Giemsa-stainable Cell Inclusions Associated with Virus Infection in Cacti," by M. Chessin, R. A. Solberg, and P. C. Fisher, 1963 (Box-folder 2/17)
  - "Factors Influencing Susceptibility to Tobacco Mosaic Virus (TMV)", 1952 (Box-folder 2/18)
  - "Faculty Turnover at MSU", 1962 (Box-folder 2/19)
  - "Germination Studies of Seeds of Native Plants", 1960 and undated (Box-folder 2/20)
  - "Growth Substances and Stunting in Virus-Infected Plants", 1957 (Box-folder 2/21)
  - "Identification of Cactus Virus," abstract, 1963 (Box-folder 2/22)
  - "The Influence of Mineral Nutrition on the Susceptibility of Nicotiana Glutinosa to Infection by Tobacco Mosaic Virus", undated (Box-folder 2/23)
  - "The Inhibitions of Tobacco Mosaic Virus by the NDBS Fraction Podophyllin," draft and correspondence, undated (Box-folder 2/24)
  - "Large-scale Use of 2,4-D on Sagebrush and Lodge pole Pine in Montana", 1970 (Box-folder 2/25)
  - "Light Quality and Photoreactivation of Plant Viruses", 1958 (Box-folder 2/26)
  - "The Mechanism of Photoreactivation of Plant Viruses", undated (Box-folder 2/27)
  - "Montana Missiles and the Arms Race", undated (Box-folder 2/28)
  - "Montana and the Nuclear Winter", undated (Box-folder 2/29)
  - "Montana and the Plowshare Program—Benefits and Risks", 1969 (Box-folder 2/30)
  - "Mutation Frequencies in Tradescantia Clone KU-9 near the Trojan Nuclear Power Plant," draft, undated (Box-folder 2/31)
  - "A New Strain of Tobacco Mosaic Virus from Lychinis alba," by M. Chessin, M. Zaitlin and R. A Solberg, 1967 (Box-folder 2/32)
  - "Nuclear Winter and the Tropics", 1992 (Box-folder 2/33)
  - "The Ozone Layer, Viruses and Plant Virus Diseases", undated (Box-folder 2/34)
  - "Photochemical Reduction of Blue Tetrazolium by Isolated Chloroplasts," by John J. Taylor and M. Chessin, 1959 (Box-folder 2/35)
  - "Photodynamic Inactivation of Infectious Nucleic Acid", 1960 (Box-folder 2/36)
  - "Photoreactivation of Clover Yellow mosaic Virus", 1965 (Box-folder 2/37)
  - "A Photoreversible Effect of Ultraviolet Light on Chloroplasts", undated (Box-folder 2/38)
  - "Physiology of Induced Responses to Biotic and Abiotic Stress", undated (Box-folder 2/39)
  - "Physiology of Plant Virus Diseases," grant report, 1959 (Box-folder 2/40)
  - "Rapid Method for Selenium Assay of Plant Material," by R. Duff and M. Chessin, 1965 (Box-folder 2/41)
  - "Plants as Hosts for Human Viruses", undated (Box-folder 2/42)
  - Review of Beyond Repair: The Ecology of Capitalism, circa 1971 (Box-folder 2/43)
  - "Science and an Informed Public: Toward a University of Survival", 1970 (Box-folder 2/44)
  - "Seed Germination of Native Plants," paper, undated (Box-folder 2/45)
  - "Selenium in the Vegetation of Malibu Beach, California", 1973 (Box-folder 2/46)
  - "A Severe Strain of Tobacco Mosaic virus from Cactus," by Lillian Giri and M. Chessin, 1975 (Box-folder 2/47)
  - "Some Notes and New Records of Plant Viruses from Montana," by H. Agrawl, L. Bos, and M. Chessin, 1962 (Box-folder 2/48)
  - "Spraying for Sagebrush Control in Montana and the West", circa 1970 (Box-folder 2/49)
  - Summary of Dissertation for Ph.D., 1950 (Box-folder 2/50)
  - "Vergleichende serologische an elektronenmik roskopische Untersuchungen an Isolaten des Kakteen-X-Virus," by others and M. Chessin, undated (Box-folder 2/51)
  - "Volitale Oils in Balsamorhiza sagitta," by M. Chessin and Muriel R. Loran, 1956 (Box-folder 2/52)
  - "Wild Plant Hosts of a Cactus Virus", 1965 (Box-folder 2/53)
  - Comments on Manuscript, undated (Box-folder 2/54)
  - Doctorate Dissertation, 1950 (Box-folder 2/55)
  - Obituary of Clancy Gordon, by M. Chessin, 1981 (Box-folder 2/56)
  - Papers by M. Chessin and Lallan Giri, undated (Box-folder 2/57)
  - Papers, drafts with correspondence, undated (Box-folder 2/58-61)
  - Publications, 1955-1975 (Box-folder 2/62)
  - Publications, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 2/63)
  - Publications, undated (Box-folder 2/64-67)
  - Publications, by Chessin and others in German, undated (Box-folder 2/68)
  - Publication list and articles, 1959-1962 and undated (Box-folder 2/69)
  - Publications and notes and illustrations, undated (Box-folder 2/70)
  - Publications and papers with comments, undated (Box-folder 2/71)
  - Report on Exchange Visit to Bulgaria, 1980 (Box-folder 2/72)
  - Speech, outline, undated (Box-folder 2/73)
  - Thesis, manuscript, undated (Box-folder 2/74)
  - Thesis, manuscript and notes, undated (Box-folder 2/75)
  - Untitled manuscript, rough draft, undated (Box-folder 2/76)
- Teaching Papers, circa 1949-1980s; Series III; 3.0 linear feet
  - Identified courses in Botany, Chemistry and Environmental Studies, course materials, circa 1950-1980s (Box 3)
  - Unidentified course materials, circa 1950-1980s (Box 4)
  - Student papers and reports, circa 1950-1980s (Box 5)
- University and Academic Service Papers, 1930-1980; Series IV; 5.4 linear feet
  - General Service Papers, 1930-1980; Subseries 1; 3.0 linear feet
    - Service Papers, 1930-1977 (Box 6)
    - Service Papers, 1976-1980 (Box 7)
    - Service Papers, 1967-1981 (Box 8)
  - Restricted Service Papers, 1969-1990; Subseries 2; 2.4 linear feet
    - Faculty Appeals Committee papers, undated (Box 9)
    - Faculty Appeals Committee papers, undated (Box 10)
    - Faculty Appeals Committee papers and other service papers, undated (Box 11)
- Research Papers, [circa 1947-1990]; Series V; 4.6 linear feet
  - Research Papers, A-C, [circa 1947-1990] (Box 12)
  - Research Papers, C-P, [circa 1947-1990] (Box 13)
  - Research Papers, P-R, [circa 1947-1990] (Box 14)
  - Research Papers, R-U, [circa 1947-1990] (Box 15)
  - Research Papers, U-W, [circa 1947-1990] (Box 16)
  - Research Notecards, undated (Box 17)
- Civic and Environmental Service Papers, 1959-1982; Series VI; 4.4 linear feet
  - Air pollution, clippings and papers, undated (Box-folder 18/1)
  - Air pollution papers by Clancy Gordon, 1958-1970 (Box-folder 18/2)
  - Acid Rain, undated (Box-folder 18/3)
  - Americans for Democratic Action, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 18/4)
  - Arms Control, correspondence with Senators Baucus and Melcher, undated (Box-folder 18/5)
  - Center of the consequences of Nuclear War, undated (Box-folder 18/6)
  - Chemical and Biological Weapons, undated (Box-folder 18/7)
  - Citizens Against Toxic Herbicides, undated (Box-folder 18/8)
  - Coal strip mining, undated (Box-folder 18/9)
  - Coalition for Peace Through Strength, undated (Box-folder 18/10)
  - Concerned Citizens for a Quality Environment, undated (Box-folder 18/11)
  - Costa Rica, undated (Box-folder 18/12)
  - Disarmament, articles, correspondence and clippings, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 18/13)
  - Disarmament, articles and correspondence, 1974-1977 and undated (Box-folder 18/14)
  - Disarmament, articles and clippings, 1976-1978 and undated (Box-folder 18/15)
  - Disarmament, SALT, 1979 (Box-folder 18/16)
  - Dissenting Democrats, clippings, 1967 and undated (Box-folder 18/17)
  - Environment, book reviews, notes and clippings, undated (Box-folder 18/18)
  - Environment, articles and clippings, undated (Box-folder 18/19)
  - Environment, film reviews, undated (Box-folder 18/20)
  - Environment, radioactivity, undated (Box-folder 18/21)
  - Environmental movement, article, undated (Box-folder 18/22)
  - Fallout Shelters, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 18/23)
  - Fort Belknap, environmental issues and survey results, undated (Box-folder 18/24)
  - Freedom Leadership Foundation, undated (Box-folder 18/25)
  - Hazardous Waste, undated (Box-folder 18/26)
  - Herbicide, 1951-1969 (Box-folder 18/27)
  - Herbicide, 1963-1974 and undated (Box-folder 18/28)
  - Herbicide, 1968-1971 and undated (Box-folder 18/29)
  - Herbicide, 1970-1978 and undated (Box-folder 18/30)
  - Herbicide, 1970-1979 and undated (Box-folder 18/31)
  - Herbicide, 1972 and undated (Box-folder 18/32)
  - Herbicide, articles and correspondence, 1972 (Box-folder 18/33)
  - Herbicide, 1972-1976 and undated (Box-folder 18/34)
  - Herbicide, 1973 (Box-folder 18/35)
  - Herbicide, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 18/36)
  - Herbicide, 2,4,5-T, undated (Box-folder 18/37)
  - Herbicide, 2,4,5-T, testimony, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 18/38)
  - Herbicide, 2,4,5-T, 1972 and undated (Box-folder 18/39)
  - Herbicide, 2,4,5-T, undated (Box-folder 18/40)
  - Herbicide, 2,4,5-T, 1980-1984 and undated (Box-folder 19/1)
  - Herbicide, 2,4,5-T hearings, undated (Box-folder 19/2)
  - Herbicide, 2,4,5-T Wartime use, 1970-1971 and undated (Box-folder 19/3)
  - Herbicide, 2,4-D and 2,4,5-T, 1980-1981 and undated (Box-folder 19/4)
  - Herbicide, campus policies, undated (Box-folder 19/5)
  - Herbicide, campus policies, undated (Box-folder 19/6)
  - Herbicide clippings, 1988 and undated (Box-folder 19/7)
  - Herbicide, commercial advertisements, undated (Box-folder 19/8)
  - Herbicide, dioxin, undated (Box-folder 19/9)
  - Herbicide and pesticide, Missoula County and Montana, 1979-1990 and undated (Box-folder 19/10)
  - Herbicide and pesticide, Western Montana, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 19/11)
  - Herbicide for Sagebrush information ‘from the establishment’, 1970 and undated (Box-folder 19/12)
  - Herbicide, Tordon, picloram, 1976 (Box-folder 19/13)
  - Institute for Policy Studies, circa 1980 (Box-folder 19/14)
  - Intercontinental Ballistic Missiles/ Anti-ballistic Missile Systems, undated (Box-folder 19/15)
  - Intercontinental Ballistic Missiles/ Anti-ballistic Missile Systems, 1968-1976 (Box-folder 19/16)
  - International Environment, undated (Box-folder 19/17)
  - Light pollution, undated (Box-folder 19/18)
  - Lodge pole thinning project, 1976 (Box-folder 19/19)
  - Microwave Radiation, articles and correspondence, 1971-1977 and undated (Box-folder 19/20)
  - Militarism, correspondence, 1972 (Box-folder 19/21)
  - Missoula issues, Brooks Street, Correspondence, 1976 (Box-folder 19/22)
  - Missoula County Zoning Commission, undated (Box-folder 19/23)
  - Montana biological weed control, undated (Box-folder 19/24)
  - Montana Missile Symposium, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 19/25)
  - Montana Missiles and the Nuclear Arms Race Conference, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 19/26)
  - Montana Missiles and the Nuclear Arms Race Conference, 1980 (Box-folder 19/27)
  - Montana Missiles and the Nuclear Arms Race Conference, proposal, undated (Box-folder 19/28)
  - Montana Weed Law, proposed modifications, undated (Box-folder 19/29)
  - Newsletters, 1965 (Box-folder 19/30)
  - Northern Plains Resource Council, undated (Box-folder 19/31)
  - Nuclear Radiation, undated (Box-folder 19/32)
  - Nuclear War, undated (Box-folder 19/33)